Olamide Adeniyi

FullStack Developer

★ https://www.oladev.net in https://linkedin/in/adeniyi-olamide
Joladev

https://www.github.com/holahmide

PROFILE

I am a Full Stack web developer with 4 years of experience and proven knowledge of programming and perseverance, through discipline and deliberate practice of conventional and modern concepts in software engineering. I enjoy solving complex problems using web technologies and building products that make an impact.

SKILLS

Frontend Development

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Typescript, React, Redux, NextJS, VueJS, Vuex, NuxtJS, GatsbyJS, Gridsome, GraphQL, SCSS, Sass, TailwindCSS, Chakra UI, SEO.

Backend Development

JavaScript, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Prisma, Laravel, Lumen, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, GraphQL, REST API, Jest, Git, CI/CD, AWS, Firebase.

Soft Skils

Agile, Curiosity, Adaptability, Problem Solving, Critical, thinking, Time Management, Communication, Leadership, Persistence.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Platform Frontend Engineer

10/2022 - 02/2023

Upstackhq ≥

San Francisco, United States

- Revamped an application (Jambird https://jambird.com), built the entire application from scratch with existing API's using ReactJs, TailwindCSS and also implemented state management for the dynamic areas of the application. Increase usage of website by 70% due to impressive UI and smooth user experience.
- Worked with a team of developers to re-engineer the structure of the company's core portal using modern code styles and conventional workflows.

Full Stack Engineer 03/2022 – 09/2022

Jetron Mall ∂

- Built an extremely scalable web application with a team of 4 developers. Enforced accessibility standards and best practices for the codebase and application development. Ensured the web application was SEO compliant allowing search engines to index it efficiently.
- Experienced the use of React, NextJS, Typescript, TDD, PDF creation kits and GraphQL.

Full Stack Developer 06/2021 – 04/2022

Brigow Homes

- Using modern technologies including React and NextJS, figma designs were converted to web pages.
- Built a robust API Backend application using NodeJS with GraphQL and REST API. Enforced healthy codebases, coding styles and standard.
- Improved the deployment speed of the Frontend application.

Full Stack Developer

Hellio Solutions @

- Implemented complex features using PHP and Javascript such as reading an excel file with large amount of customer contacts. Crafted, audited and improved designs, accessibility and the overall experience of the product.
- Increased File loading and reading time by 80% during a test case of 600,000 contacts in an excel document uploaded on the server.

Full Stack Developer

Urella

- Built a church management application for a startup with a team of web developers. Implemented attendance tracking, financial record keeping, membership authentication, data presentation and visualization, COVID-19 seat tracker and crowd control.
- Development technologies include Laravel, PHP, JavaScript and VueJS.

Full Stack Developer 05/2019 – 09/2020

Gilgal House Media ≥

• Built an extremely scalable web application and obtained relevant experiences in data administration, hosting, web server management, CI/CD, VueJS, Vuex and Git.

• Built a CBT application for the company to access new recruits based on some preset questions and interview parameters. Enhanced HR team recruitment method accuracy by 90%. Introduced automated mailing and attendance update alert features.

Frontend Developer 02/2019 – 09/2019

Freelance @

Built and maintained stunning web application for my clients.

EDUCATION

BEng. Information Engineering

07/2017

Landmark University &

Best Department Graduating Student with a CGPA of 4.87.

COURSES

React - The Complete Guide.

Udemy

By Maximilian Schwarzmüller

Advanced CSS and Sass

Udemy

By Jonas Schmedtmann

Javascript Essential Training

LinkedIn

By Morten Rand-Hendriksen

Project Management

Landmark University